<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023 on MrBocch</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 on MrBocch</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 23:15:17 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Before the year ends</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/2023/newyear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 23:15:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/2023/newyear/</guid>
      <description>2023 I dont like to make a big deal out of the earth making a full rotation around the sun, but I like to reflect on how is the me from January 1st different from the me of today.
I with out a doubt know more about programming than I did then.
I learned and fell in love with ruby, I understand OOP more than i did then.
With ruby I tackled a little bit of leetcode.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;2023&#34;&gt;2023&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dont like to make a big deal out of the earth
making a full rotation around the sun, but I like to reflect
on how is the me from January 1st different from the me of
today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I with out a doubt know more about programming than I did then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned and fell in love with ruby, I understand OOP more than i did then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ruby I tackled a little bit of leetcode. From seeking to write more expresive leetcode solutions I decided to look into Haskell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From reading a Haskell book, I learned what higher order functions actually mean, I understand recursion better, I know what tail call optimization is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned how to code in a group for a school project. I had to learn a little SQL for this school project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, this year I have been more productive with learning computer science than any year before, but I feel like I could of done alot more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am greatfull for this great year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2024&#34;&gt;2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the game plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are several books that I must read this year, &lt;strong&gt;and actually finish them rather then leave them half read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get Programming with Haskell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Will Kurt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;SICP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (im really exited about this one, will even follow along with the course on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-J_xL4IGhJA&amp;list=PLE18841CABEA24090&#34;&gt;youtube&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Rust Book&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (I want to try out tauri framework)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crafting Interpreters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Robert Nystrom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any book on APL, it looks soo interesting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I image that these books are not the kind you could read in a couple of sittings. They very dense with information and I expect to struggle alot reading them but I believe they will make me a better programmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have other goals outside of programming but I want to keep those for my self 😊.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways here is for a good year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;img/celebration.gif&#34;; style=&#39;margin: 0 auto;&#39;&gt;

</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
